welcome back to am Northwest you know
when it comes to Vintage treasures and
knowing what they're worth our next
expert our next guest is an expert here to
share as always helpful tips we welcome
back antique appraiser Gary germer great
to see you you too thanks for having me
back um it's always fun to find out what
you find and and prize and all this so
okay let's start I know you're a huge
Beatles fan I am I'm a big Beatles and
and pop me pop culture F yeah I brought
this today because it's a obviously black
light poster obvious to you and I it's
a black light post CU we're old yeah
you get under 30 they don't know what
you're talking about about a black light
I love black light posters and uh and
so they're getting they're kind of being
rediscovered by the 20s something like
it's really cool it's a black light
poster you know and um um and so
but if you find one rolled up that you
had when you were in college and you
stuck it in a closet somewhere they're
becoming h again and of course subject
matters but any of the black light posters
can go from 100 bucks and up beetles
and stuff related uh this was a special
pressing for and explain what a black
light poster is when you yeah
explain no go ahead explain well as
you look here it's rather flat looking
uh you know it's green but when you shut
the lights off and you simply have a
black light going it glows it looks
threedimensional and it's completely
different look looks awesome you know and
unfortunately we can't
show that that okay and then the two
little stuffed toys down here stuffed toys
are old STI animals and I brought those
because often times you'll find these in
the states in the closet or whatever
stif if you're looking at stuff animals
were kind of like The Cadillacs of
those they're the best ones and usually
people know them because they'll have
the little button in their ear and but if
you get before you know the older ones
the parents would take the button out so
the kid wouldn't chew on it and choke
so there's other ways of telling they're
made of M hair they'll have glass
eyes the noses mouths will be stitched
and often times they uh swivel and
stuff these are from about the 1960s
okay um they the company started in late
1800s so if you get back there you're
talking about significant money if they're
in really great shape these here are
fun to collect and find uh the prices on
these little animals in about the $ 30
to $4 range when you find them so they're
not huge money but if you find them in
the back of your closet or you remember
having them a little kid don't throw
them out they're really kind of fun well
and what you've said to me in the past
is what's important is that there may
be somebody out there who really wants
that last one exactly you know
to complete their collection
SE okay now this glass uh piece
I not sure what it is yeah
it this I I brought that because it took
me forever to figure out what it was
it's a it's a obviously glass bowl a
couple lips and I kept think what would you
pour out of it so you're thinking
around 1,800 or earlier give or take um
and it would be used on your dining
table and it's called a rinsing bowl and
they would put some water and some ice
in it and it was before the mid 1800s
when you had a different wine glass for
every kind of wine you had a wine glass
so between courses you're going to go to
a white wine you wanted to chill it so
you'd put your wine glass in there oh
and let it soak and chill the glass and
rinse out the red wine and the little lip
kept it from rolling around and around
and around look at that that's fun I
love that yeah absolutely useless today
but I think they're hey that's fun I
like it okay and this piece is an Asian
piece so tell me about this it is it's
these you'll find these quite often these
carved pieces and you got to think of
Chinese furniture like they have the big
beds that are almost like rooms or pie
and they'll have these panels in there
that are carved like this or I actually
have a long one like this with yeah so I
understand what you're talking about yeah
be on a screen or something like that
well the thing is is that this is all
the work this is a really nice really
thick on some are shallower carved and
that's kind you can kind of Judge their
value based on that um so is it more
value when they're raised out of the frame
well it's more three-dimensional
carving you know so the carving is more
detailed and gilded what's interesting
though is the way they built their
furniture that later if the were wor out
or you're going to you want to change
your furniture they could pop these out
like a window out of a window sill and
then they could build again and then they
would put build it to put the art back
in wow so it was where this was the hard
part to make so they always hung on to
that so you might have a piece of furniture
that's 50 or 100 years old but the
carving could be 200 years old and how
much do you think this is worth that's
worth probably in the neighborhood of
$400 wow yeah I I get that okay now you
have some vases over here or do you want
to talk about the pictures either one
we can go the vases let's talk about
those okay now you're going to find a lot
of this out of Estates and this is the
sort of thing that got uh eBay going that
in Pez dispensers you know everybody was
trading and collecting old American art
pottery and then the markets come way
down so you have um uh the different
pieces here like Roseville Pottery these
three in the front are what you called
production pieces meaning they were in
a mold you know and they could produce
them quickly right this would go originally
maybe in the 1990s this was selling
for $125 now it's maybe 20 bucks oh
interesting okay there are some rare pieces
but the production pieces bind lart but
the one in your hand is a slip glaze and
that dates a little earlier 195
or so and um it's hand painted
as opposed to these like I said are
production painted the kind of details are
picked out but the production pieces uh
I mean the hand painted and if you get
any of the companies their top of their
line was anything hand painted the
market has come down on them from what
it was but they're still very strong
because they are actual hand painted
works of art wow Gary thank you so much
always very informative I appreciate it